

# Maximilian Schaum

Software Engineer Frontend React.JS

- **\** 01622715832
- ★ https://max-s-resume.netlify.app/
- 12529 Schönefeld, Deutschland

#### SUMMARY

Reliable and motivated Full-Stack Web Developer with vast Tech experience. Specialized in Front-End Development with React.js, with lots of experience in Back-End. Passionate for creative solutions to concrete problems with the help of the Web. Adaptable team player, with the ability to work independently and the willingness to go the extra mile.

#### EXPERIENCE

#### Full-Stack Web Developer | Founder

Webentwicklung 030 Berlin GmbH

- Optimization of customer Web pages in regard to organic recruitment increase from 0 1 applicants to 10 20 applicants per month
- Implementing interfaces to external job boards for automatic transfer of jobs RESTful API
- · Self-Developed Website Management System for customers
- · Online analysis to automatically test webpages for different quality criteria
- CRM Web-Application for recruiting of personnel
- Chrome Extension to automatically scrape data with direct interface to the CRM Application RESTful API
- Webpage design, creation and SEO optimization React.js

#### **Working Student Web Development**

VIPCRUITER GmbH

06/2020 - 03/2021

09/2019 - 06/2020

03/2021 - Present

- Relaunch of multiple webpages of WordPress to Gatsby.js (React.js)
- Webpage maintenance and optimization

### **Working Student IT / Controlling**

Mercedes-Benz AG

- · Reporting Dashboard Development
- Excel VBA Programming
- · Process modeling and automation

#### **Working Student Web Development**

SCHAUM MASSIVHAUS

05/2017 - 08/2019

09/2014 - 04/2017

- · Webpage creation, maintenance and optimization HTML, CSS und JavaScript
- · IT-Administration and accounting

## IT-Specialist for software development

IGEPA group GmbH & Co. KG

- JD Edwards E1 Database Programming
- Java Web Application and Interfaces

### EDUCATION

#### **Mathematics / Computer Science**

2021

Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin - Bachelors

1/2

### SKILLS

React.js Meteor.js Advanced Expert Node.js Advanced Gatsby.js Expert TailwindCSS Github Actions Advanced Expert HTML Typescript Intermediate Expert Javascript / ES6 Intermediate Next.js Expert CSS Beginner Expert Express.js MongoDB Expert Svelte Beginner **REST API** Advanced Vue.js Beginner LANGUAGES

Deutsch Native Englisch Fluent